Julie Pitt

http://yakticus.github.io/

SUMMARY

WHAT is usually more significant than HOW. When building something new, I often use the "what" to shine a light on what's extraneous, overly complex or misaligned with the goal.

The tl;dr: 15 years combined experience building teams, scalable APIs and distributed systems; most recently co-founded startup to bring autonomous agents with "common sense" intelligence into the world; built streaming service at Netflix during initial device and international roll-outs; international speaker; Scala, Node.js, AWS and many more

EXPERIENCE

Order of Magnitude Labs - Co-founder

March 2014 - Present

What: Introduce autonomous agents that learn "common sense" to problems that today's smartest machines can't solve

How:

- After a period of bootstrapping, secured seed funding from a major VC
- Through research and experimentation, uncovered the limits of today's deep learning technologies in solving "common sense" problems
- Developed novel IP enabling autonomous agents to learn and act in messy and dynamic environments despite ambiguity

Lyve Minds - Senior Engineering Manager

December 2012 - February 2014

What: Bring forgotten memories to life and ensure that new ones are safe and accessible

How:

- Hired and led service engineering team, with emphasis on client integration, availability, fault tolerance and scale
- Built AWS-deployed services and protocols in Scala
- Standardized protocol and server stack to minimize design, build and release friction

StumbleUpon – Tech lead/manager, recommendations infrastructure

August 2012 - December 2012

What: Introduce people to new ideas across the web that extend beyond their immediate social bubbles

How:

- Hired a small engineering team to re-architect StumbleUpon's recommendations infrastructure in under 3 months
- Built an initial proof-of-concept prototype in Scala

Netflix - Manager, streaming server engineering

July 2010 - August 2012

What: Connect people worldwide to movies they love.

How:

 Managed a medium-sized team of engineers responsible for developing the application tier that drives Netflix streaming playback San Francisco Bay Area, California julie@yakticus.com +1 (925) 980-2217

Twitter - @yakticus LinkedIn - Julie Pitt github - yakticus StackOverflow - julie

SKILLS

Management

hiring, cross-functional project management, building orgs

Functional programming

Scala

API design

REST, JSON, Protobuf, XML

Distributed systems

AWS, EC2, Reactive paradigm, Akka, Finagle

Web & full stack development

Node.js, JavaScript, Scala.js

Public speaking

tech conferences

Machine Learning

probability theory, information theory, Bayesian methods, deep neural networks, linear algebra

Past & Hobby

Java, RDBMS, MySQL, Oracle, Arduino, Python, PERL

EDUCATION

Coursera

2012-present

continued education in C.S.

coursework: Functional programming in Scala; Principles of Reactive Programming; Machine Learning

University of California, Davis

2005-2007

- Launched streaming service in Canada, Latin America and the UK
- Rapid innovation on PS3, XBox, Wii, AppleTV, Android and iOS while delivering quality service for hundreds of consumer electronics device models
- Scaled the team from 2 to 8 engineers as server traffic increased from 500 million to 3.5 billion requests per day
- Led a cross-functional effort to re-architect credentials on streaming devices

Netflix - Senior Software Engineer

December 2008 - July 2010

What: Connect people to movies they love.

How:

- Developed scalable Java server application to support explosive growth in Netflix streaming volume and device breadth
- Built server functionality for 1st & 2nd generation streaming app on the PS3
- Integrated server DRM & protocol enhancements for first ever Wii console streaming app
- Introduced server delivery of subtitles & alternate language tracks to Netflix streaming devices
- Added 1.5 years of life to infrastructure delivering customers' viewing history

NASA Ames Research Center - Senior Software Engineer

July 2008 - December 2008

What: As part of the Constellation program, bring the International Space Station up-to-date, and eventually bring humans to the Moon and to Mars.

How:

- Designed and developed RDF triple store persistence API in Java
- Cross-functional liason between development and ontology modeling teams
- Evangelized and implemented development practices on the team, including TDD, continuous integration, use of Subversion, Hudson, Maven and Artifactory

Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory - *Software Engineer, project lead*

June 2001 - July 2008

What: Support various missions ranging from follow-on research to the Human Genome Project to Biodefense in the wake of 9/11.

How

- Built Java applications to bring together disparate structured and unstructured data sources for use by scientists and analysts
- Built PERL/CGI applications to process and make accessible data underpinning the Human Genome Project and beyond

coursework for M.S. in Computer Science

University of California, Davis

1999-2002

B.S. Applied Mathematics, minor in Computer Science